All right,
get out of there.
Let's go.
All the way down
and take a seat.
Let's go. Stop your
dragging. Let's go! Move!
Let's go. Let's go.
Let's go! Line up! Line up!
- Move! Move! Right turn!
Stay with me! PIERPONT:
Keep your head down!
Line up! Line up!
Everybody ready?
Come on.
Line up!
Get off me!
Come on.
- One...
Now march us to the changing
rooms. ...two, three.
Go. Let's go.
Line up!
I know you.
You just got paroled out of
here. You didn't last very long.
When was that?
Eight weeks ago.
Did nine years.
John. John Dillinger.
That's right.
My friends call me John.
But a son-of-a-bitch screw like you
better address me as Mr. Dillinger.
Open it! Open it or
I'll blow you in half.
Against the wall.
Take your
clothes off, now!
You did it, kid.
Sure did, Walter.
Give me
the goddamn jacket.
Red!
Come on. Hurry up! PIERPONT: Get
undressed. Take your clothes off.
Come on.
You eyeballing me,
you son of a bitch?
Cut it out,
Shouse!
Shouse! Shouse!
Lockdown!
Bring them in
from the yard!
There they are!
Walter! Come on.
Walter Dietrich's dead
'cause of you.
The bastard guard wouldn't
do what he was told, Johnny.
Homer?
Just let him
have it, Johnny.
Pete?
It's up to you.
How far is the farm?
3.2 miles.
We're ready!
Okay. Let's go!
Burn these,
okay, honey?
Thanks for
getting us out, Red.
It was Johnny's plan.
Yeah, but thanks.
Take me with you, mister.
I can't, darling.
I'm sorry.
Welcome back, Pete.
Let's go to Chicago
and make some money.
Floyd, halt!
Melvin, look out!
Pretty Boy Floyd,
you are under arrest.
It's Charles.
Charles Floyd.
Who are you? Melvin Purvis,
Bureau of Investigation.
Where is your friend,
Harry Campbell?
I believe
you've killed me.
So you can go
rot in hell.
Sport.
Red, call Oscar.
Okay.
Hi, there, doll.
Let's switch out the shorts.
We gonna
use Berman?
Yeah. Get a Plymouth
and an Essex.
Where them other gals?
You get a hold of Marty?
Sure did.
How you doing,
Mr. Johnny?
Doing great, Sport.
The main spring's too tight
on this one. Jammed twice.
I cut off
one coil.
And it rides up
and to the right.
I widen port.
Hey, Red.
Hi, Harry.
Harry, this is Pete.
Pete, this is Harry Berman.
Hi, Pete.
How you doing?
So, what do we got? Got a
couple of nice straight eights.
Bored them out. Rebuilt
the carburetors myself.
These are some
really fast cars.
Perfect work cars for
a couple of gentlemen.
Johnny, how are you?
Good.
Marty,
tell me that me
and my boys are okay.
As long as you stay
in East Chicago,
you're in safe haven,
any time you want.
Extra cake's in here.
Thanks.
Hey, Anna.
I opened up in Chicago on Halsted
now. Come by and see the girls.
How are you?
On the floor! Now! Now! Do it!
Do it! On the floor, now! Now!
Let's play a game, Mr. President.
It's called Spin the Dial.
You, hands up!
Come on. And, you, sit down!
On the floor!
Relax, pops.
Open it up.
Empty it! Move, move!
Shut up!
It's one of these.
You can be a dead hero
or a live coward.
Get it open.
All of it!
You, hands up.
Come on!
Empty it! All of it!
Hey, sit down!
Push it to me!
And don't move!
We got company!
Move out of there!
You can put it away. Not here for
your money. Here for the bank's money.
I said,
move it out of there!
What for?
Come here, sister.
Let's take a ride.
Get down!
Beat it.
You, too, sister.
Come here.
There you go, doll.
Something to remember me by.
You know, when I'm not doing
this, I'm a scout for the movies.
Really?
Join hands.
We'll freeze here!
No. You'll worm your way out
of there in about 10 minutes.
Why do we
need this?
Because criminals flee in fast
automobiles across state lines,
thereby defeating
local jurisdiction
because there is no federal
police force to stop them.
By my tally, your
Bureau wants to spend
more taxpayers' dollars
catching crooks
than what the crooks you
catch stole in the first place.
Well, that's ridiculous.
The Bureau has apprehended
kidnappers and
bank robbers who have
stolen up to and in excess of... Really?
How many have you
apprehended?
We have arrested and
arraigned 213 wanted felons.
No, I mean you, Director
Hoover. How many?
Well, as Director,
I administer.
How many have you
arrested personally?
I have never
arrested anybody.
You've never
Well, of course not.
I am an administrator.
With no field experience.
You are shockingly
unqualified, aren't you, sir?
You have never
personally conducted
a criminal investigation
in the field in your life.
I think you're a front.
I think your prowess
as a lawman is a myth
created from the hoopla of headlines
by Mr. Suydam, your publicist there.
Crimebusters, G-men, you're
setting yourself up as a czar?
That's running wild
in my estimation.
A crime is what
runs wild.
If this country requires
a Bureau such as yours,
I question whether you are
the person fit to run it.
Well, I will not be judged by a
kangaroo court of venal politicians.
Your appropriation
increase is denied.
Feed the following
to Walter Winchell.
McKellar is a Neanderthal, and he is
on a personal vendetta to destroy me.
We will not contest him
in his committee room.
We will fight him
on the front page.
Where is John Dillinger?
Agent Purvis,
congratulations.
Thank you, sir.
May I ask why?
They're ready for him.
This is Henry Suydam. He is
our expert in press relations.
Congratulations
for Pretty Boy Floyd,
for which you have
my personal gratitude.
Second, you are,
as of this moment,
the Special Agent in Charge
of the Chicago field office.
Are you up to that
task, Agent Purvis?
Absolutely, sir.
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
Today, I am declaring the United
States of America's first War on Crime.
And I'd like to introduce one of our
finest G-men, Agent Melvin Purvis.
Agent Purvis will be in charge
of the field office in Chicago,
the center of the crime
wave sweeping America.
His task will be to get Public
Enemy Number One, John Dillinger.
Director?
Mr. Purvis?
Say a few words,
would you?
Mr. Purvis, how did you
run down Pretty Boy Floyd?
Through an apple orchard.
Mr. Tolson, when he's done, you
tell him if he needs anything,
you'll get it for him.
And tell him
he may call me J. E.
Yeah, but people say John Dillinger's
a lot smarter and a lot tougher.
Well, nevertheless,
we will get him.
What makes
you so sure?
We have two things
Dillinger does not.
What are they?
The Bureau's modern techniques
of fighting crime scientifically
and the visionary
leadership
of our Director,
J. Edgar Hoover.
The broad over there is looking at me.
She likes me.
How you doing,
sweetheart?
Alvin.
Good to see you.
How you doing?
Homer. Pete.
Me, Freddy and Doc are
looking to snatch a fellow.
He's a Saint Paul banker, Ed
Bremer. We need a few more hands.
I don't like kidnapping.
Well, robbing banks
is getting tougher.
The public don't
like kidnapping.
Who gives a damn
what the public likes?
I do.
I hide out among them.
We gotta care
what they think.
We also got a mail train
we're looking at, too.
By the way, if somebody was to get
pinched, who knows their way around?
Syndicate lawyer named Piquett,
Louis Piquett. We all use him.
What's it all about,
this train?
Needs two or three more real
right guys to stick it up.
Be ready in
a couple of months.
About $1,700,000. It's a
Federal Reserve shipment.
It's the kind of score
you go away on after.
Where you gonna go?
I don't know. Brazil,
Cuba. I like Varadero Beach.
What about you?
No plans.
Yeah, well,
you ought to.
What we're doing
won't last forever.
We're having too
good a time today.
We ain't thinking
about tomorrow.
Keep me in mind on the train,
would you? All right. Thanks.
You know how much they made
taking that Hamm Brewery guy?
$100,000.
Simmer down, Homer.
Come on, fellas.
Let's go to the bar.
I got three broads
convinced I own the place.
See you.
Is Homer staying
steady enough?
Homer's fine.
One rule I learned
from Walter Dietrich,
never work with people
who are desperate.
Yeah, well, I got a rule,
too. Stay away from the women.
Without women, it's
like back in the stir.
That's why they
invented whores.
Hey, hey, Anna.
How are you doing,
big boy?
Who's this?
Veronica.
Veronica, Red.
Hi, Johnny.
Hey, Anna.
I don't know why you gave
that fellow the go-by,
but I'm awful glad
you did.
What's your name?
Billie Frechette.
Can I buy you a drink?
Okay.
You got a name?
Yeah.
Jack.
You dance, Jack?
I don't know how.
Come on.
How come you don't
know how to dance?
Frechette.
That French?
On my father's side.
There's an "e" at the end.
This is a two-step.
Blackbird
Where somebody waits for me
Sugar's sweet, so is he
Daddy's French.
What's on the other side?
My mama's
a Menominee Indian, okay?
Most men don't like that.
I ain't most men.
Yeah?
And I've been a dice girl, and I
check coats at the Steuben Club.
And what do you do?
I'm catching up.
Meeting somebody
like you,
dark and beautiful,
like that bird
in that song.
Blackbird, bye-bye
No one here can love
Or understand me
You cold?
What is it exactly
you do for a living?
I'm John Dillinger.
I rob banks.
That's where all these
people here put their money.
Why did you
tell me that?
You could have
made up a story.
I'm not gonna
lie to you.
That's a serious thing to
say to a girl you just met.
I know you.
Well, I don't know you.
I haven't been anyplace.
Well, some of the places
I've been ain't so hot.
Where I'm going is
a whole lot better.
Want to come along?
Boy, you are in a hurry!
If you were looking at what I'm
looking at, you'd be in a hurry, too.
Well,
it's me they're
looking at this time.
You're beautiful.
They're looking at me
because they're not used to
having a girl in
their restaurant
in a $3 dress.
Listen, doll.
That's 'cause they're all
about where people come from.
The only thing that's important
is where somebody's going.
Where are you going?
Anywhere I want.
Let's get out of here.
Hey, Johnny!
Go wait for me outside.
Gil.
Ever since I got out, I've
been working for Frank Nitti.
These guys are connected to
everybody all over the country now.
He looks like a barber.
Phil D'Andrea. Every time I
read about one of your bank jobs
where you give the customers
back their money, you crack me up.
You need anything,
ask Gilbert.
Gilbert knows
how to find me.
Thank you.
Where'd that girl go?
I don't know, sir.
She jumped in a cab
and took off.
This is
Lowell Thomas.
From West Virginia
comes accusations
by the Carnegie CoaI company
of Red influence
on the United Mine
Workers' strike.
Meanwhile, in Racine, Wisconsin,
after raiding the American Trust Bank,
Public Enemy Number One
John Dillinger
roams the wilds pursued
by the hounds of justice.
And in Geneva,
the League of Nations
voted the USSR
full membership.
According to the bank
teller, Barbara Patzke,
this is
John Dillinger's coat.
It's made by Shragge
Quality out of St. Louis.
Price, $35, windproof
32-ounce wool. Top stitching.
Thank you, Agent Baum.
Agents in our offices
across the country
are identifying every store in the
United States that sold this overcoat.
Then we will cross-reference
every Dillinger associate
at locales where
that coat was sold.
He was in a place.
He got cold.
He bought a coat.
Unless he was
traveling through,
he was being
harbored nearby.
If he returns,
we will be there.
It is by such methods that our
Bureau will get John Dillinger.
Now, Doris,
would you please contact
the Chicago area telephone
exchange supervisors. There are six.
Request appointments for
Carter Baum and myself.
Gentlemen,
shortly you will be provided
Thompson submachine guns, BARs
and a.351 Winchester
semi-automatic rifle.
We are pursuing hardened
killers. They will be dangerous.
And those of you who aren't
prepared for that should go.
And if you are going
to go, please go now.
This is a phone call
conversation
from a car dealership
from 27 minutes ago.
Harry Berman.
When you drop it, leave
the keys on the floorboard.
I got a DeSoto.
Okay.
Interior's no good.
How did we get
to Berman?
Off the Dillinger coat.
The coat was bought
in Cicero, lllinois,
a few doors down from
Berman's dealership.
Now, we know Berman. He's been supplying
cars to the Syndicate since Capone.
When Dillinger
bought that coat,
he must have been at
Berman's switching cars.
As soon as they call to drop
the DeSoto, we'll tail it.
I want men on this
around the clock.
May I check
your coat, sir?
Yes, thank you.
You ran out on me.
You left me standing
on the sidewalk.
If you're
gonna be my girl,
you're gonna have to swear to me
that you'll never ever do that again.
Hey, I'm not your girl.
Brown overcoat.
And I'm not
gonna say that.
I'm waiting.
So am I.
"I'm never gonna run out on
you ever again." Say the words.
No.
My coat.
Well, I ain't ever gonna run
out on you, and that's a promise.
Well, I want to run
out of here, so, lady...
Hit the road, sport.
Keep the tip.
You ain't getting other people's
hats and coats no more neither.
Why'd you do that?
'Cause you're with me now.
I don't know
anything about you.
I was raised on a farm
in Mooresville, Indiana.
My mama died
when I was three.
My daddy beat the hell out of me 'cause
he didn't know no better way to raise me.
I like baseball, movies, good
clothes, fast cars, whiskey and you.
What else
you need to know?
Have a seat.
You been living here long?
Yeah.
Since yesterday.
Hey.
I got you something.
When I was a girl,
we went to live on the
reservation in Flandreau
'cause my daddy died.
In Flandreau,
nothing ever happened.
And when I was 13, I went to live
in Milwaukee with my Aunt Ines.
We had a lot of
Indian friends,
and we went around to
churches and put on plays.
And nothing exciting ever
happened there, either.
So I haven't been anywhere or done
anything except come to Chicago
and try to make my way.
You're all packed.
Well, baby,
I'm gonna
take you with me.
And you're gonna start a whole
new exciting kind of life.
And what do you want?
Everything.
Right now.
Purvis.
Berman dropped the DeSoto at
Sherone Apartments 20 minutes ago.
Men go in and out of an apartment
rented to a Miss Vi Scott.
They carry heavy suitcases. One
of them looks like Dillinger.
Where are your men?
In cars on Clarendon
and Wilson Avenue.
Blocking vehicles?
The alley?
Who has a line of sight
on the DeSoto to you?
Are they aware that we are
here? Any rapid movements?
No.
Carter,
you keep an eye on
the DeSoto from there.
Barton, you're with me.
Yes?
I'm Special Agent Melvin
Purvis, Miss Scott.
Are you here
by yourself?
No. I'm here
with my fiancé.
And what is
your fiancé's name?
Leonard McHenry.
May we come in?
Well, please.
I'm perfectly safe,
but come on in.
Something wrong?
You have identification?
Yeah, sure.
Honey, would you get my driver's
license? It's in my jacket pocket.
Sure.
I know you.
You're...
You're Melvin Purvis.
Right?
Yeah. I seen your picture.
And what do you do
for a living, Leonard?
I travel
in ladies' shoes.
Show him, honey.
Cute, huh?
Well, you enjoy the rest
of your dinner, Mr. McHenry.
Thanks.
Good night.
No one in or out. I'll get
the others. You stay here.
You watch that door
from right there.
Get the men
from Sheridan.
Bureau of Investigation.
What's your name?
You wanna know
my name?
Come on.
Baum, you keep an eye
on the alley.
Barton?
Barton.
Where is he?
They're headed east!
Who was in
the blocking car?
That was us.
We heard gunfire
so we came here.
Who was it?
Dillinger?
The man we let get away
wasn't John Dillinger.
That was Baby Face Nelson.
Get on the floor!
Now! Go!
Y'all get up
against that wall.
Go on, all of you. PIERPONT:
This is a stick-up! Up!
Put them up! Up!
Down on the floor,
now! Down!
Put them up! Come on.
Put them up!
This is a stick-up!
Let's go. Come on.
Up!
Where I can
see them, up!
Customers, stay calm.
Don't move.
Hey! You! Up!
Hands up!
Move! Empty it!
John Dillinger held up
a bank for $74,000
while you failed
to arrest Nelson.
Sir, I take
full responsibility.
And I would like
to make a request.
That we transfer men with
special qualifications
to augment the staff
here in Chicago.
There are some former
Texas and Oklahoma lawmen
currently with
the Bureau in Dallas.
I thought you understood
what I'm building.
A modern force of professional
young men of the best sort.
I'm afraid our type
cannot get the job done.
Excuse me,
I cannot hear you.
Our type cannot
get the job done.
I cannot hear you.
Our type cannot
get the job done.
Without qualified help,
I would have to resign
this appointment.
Otherwise, I am leading
my men to slaughter.
Mr. Tolson will call you,
Agent Purvis.
Did he say what
he looked like?
Didn't say.
You gentlemen
need any help?
Thank you, no.
Shine?
Morning.
How you doing?
I'm doing all right.
Agent Winstead?
That's right.
It's a pleasure.
Welcome to Chicago. We have a lot
of work to do here on Mr. Dillinger.
Another time.
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
Have a nice day.
Put Johnny Patton down front
on the other four tracks.
It's hot out, right?
Yes, Frank.
Ever since those pricks
shot me, I can't get warm.
What?
Some people from
Chicago over there.
Johnny.
What do you say we meet you
in Tucson around the 25th?
Okay.
All right.
I heard one today.
Indiana paper,
"Wanted, John Dillinger,
dead or dead."
I think we wore out
the Midwest for a while.
What?
Come out to the Colonial tonight.
It's our joint. Be my guest.
The best steaks in Miami.
You're not gonna
take our picture, are you?
No pictures.
All right.
We'll be there.
Thank you for taking me
on this trip.
You going somewhere,
doll? Am I?
No.
Don't kid a kidder.
Then don't play me
for a fool.
We both know I end up back
checking coats at the Steuben Club,
one way or the other.
What does that mean?
You don't think past today
or tomorrow. And eventually,
they will catch you
or kill you
and I don't want to be
there when that happens.
Who gave you
a crystal ball?
I don't need one.
Ask Homer.
Ask Homer what?
And his goddamn joke,
"dead or dead."
You ain't going nowhere,
you hear me?
I'm gonna die an old man
in your arms.
We're too good for them.
They ain't tough enough,
smart enough or fast enough.
I hit any bank
I want any time.
They got to be at
every bank all the time.
That's why we're
on top of the world.
Ain't nobody
lay a glove on us.
No.
I ain't going nowhere.
Neither are you.
What do you got
to say about that?
Hi, folks.
Afternoon. Got a reservation for
a Mr. and Mrs. Frank Sullivan.
I can send up some sandwiches
and beer if you like.
That'd be swell.
Some friends of mine
should be here already,
a J.C. Davies
and a Mr. Clark?
Out shopping, I believe.
I'll let them know you're
in when they get back.
Okey-doke.
The elevator's
right down that way.
Thank you very much.
You look like you
could use some company.
How's about me and my friend Prince
Albert come and pay you a visit?
Get on in here,
both of you.
Johnny! Johnny!
Put some clothes on, miss.
What the hell
happened, boys?
There was a fire
in the hotel.
Firemen found our guns.
They called the cops.
Where they taking you?
We're getting
shanghaied to Ohio.
Where's Billie?
Your girl's been put on
a bus back to Chicago.
We ain't holding her.
Right this way.
Well,
here's the man who
killed Pretty Boy Floyd.
Damn good thing he was pretty,
'cause he sure wasn't Whiz Kid Floyd.
Tell me something,
Mr. Purvis.
That fellow, the one who got
killed at the Sherone Apartments,
the newspaper said
you found him alive.
It's the eyes,
ain't it?
They look at you
right before they go.
And then they just
drift away into nothing.
That'll keep
you up nights.
And what keeps you up
nights, Mr. Dillinger?
Coffee.
You act like a confident
man, Mr. Purvis.
You got a few qualities.
Probably pretty good
from a distance,
especially when you got
the fellow outnumbered.
But up close,
toe to toe,
when somebody's about to
die right here, right now,
I'm used to that.
What about you?
Goodbye, Mr. Dillinger.
I'll see you
down the road.
No, you will not.
The only way that you
will leave a jail cell
is when we take you out
to execute you.
Well, we'll see
about that.
You ought to get yourself
another line of work, Melvin.
Hey, I was just kidding.
I believe I'm gonna let you
boys keep me here a while.
We'd like that, Johnny, but
don't get too comfortable.
They're moving you.
Where to?
Indiana.
Why?
I have absolutely nothing
I want to do in Indiana.
He's here.
Back up, fellas.
Back up.
We'll take custody now.
Take the manacles off.
Are you glad
to see Indiana again?
About as glad as Indiana
is to see me, I suppose.
Did you smuggle the guns into
Indiana State Penitentiary
for the big break
of September 26th?
Right now, you're
too inquisitive, buddy.
Put your arm
around Dillinger.
Hey, when was the last time
you were in Mooresville?
Ten years ago.
I was a wild boy, and,
well, I was foolish.
I held up a grocery store,
which I never should have done
'cause Mr. Morgan was a good man.
And they sentenced me to 10 years in
the state penitentiary for a $50 theft.
When I was in prison,
I met a lot of good fellows.
So sure, yeah,
I helped set up the break
at Michigan City. Why not?
I stick with my pals
and my pals stick with me.
Johnny, how long does it
take you to go through a bank?
Oh, about one minute,
40 seconds.
Flat.
Let's go.
Mr. Johnny,
your lawyer's here.
You come highly
recommended by Alvin Karpis.
At the arraignment,
they're gonna try and
transfer me to the state pen.
What can you do for me?
What's on your mind?
The electric chair.
Your Honor, are we to have an arraignment
in accord with the laws of this nation
or is the State to be permitted to
incite an atmosphere of prejudice?
The very air reeks with the
bloody rancor of intolerant malice!
The clanging of shackles
brings to our minds
the dungeons of the czars,
not the flag-bedecked liberty
of an American courtroom.
I request the court to direct that
those shackles be removed forthwith.
This is a very dangerous
man, Your Honor.
And I'm responsible for the
safeguarding of this prisoner.
Are you a lawyer? What right do
you have to address this court?
All right. Remove the
shackles from the prisoner.
Your Honor, we would like
to relocate the prisoner.
Only Indiana State
Penitentiary in Michigan City
can guarantee
Dillinger will not escape.
Sheriff Holley?
I concur, Your Honor.
Sheriff Holley, I think this is a
very nice jail you have right here.
What makes you think there's
something wrong with it?
There's nothing
wrong with my jail.
It's the strongest jail
in Indiana.
That's what I thought.
But of course, I don't want
to embarrass Mrs. Holley.
I appreciate she's a woman
and she's afraid of an escape.
Oh, no. I'm not afraid
of an escape.
I can take care of John
Dillinger or any other prisoner.
Okay.
Dillinger will stay here.
Thank you,
Your Honor.
The defense will need four
months to prepare itself.
It should take 10 days.
To go to trial in 10 days would
be a legal lynching of this lad.
There's a law
against lynching.
against murder!
Then observe
the law part.
Or just stand Dillinger
up against a wall
and shoot him.
Just shoot him.
Then there's no need to throw away
the State's money on this mockery.
Calm down.
I apologize to the court.
Bob and I respect
each other very much.
Watch out or he'll be putting
his arm around you, too.
Trial starts in one
month on March 12th.
Attaboy, counselor.
Open the gate.
Hey, Cahoon!
Come here a minute.
Come on, Sam.
You and me's going places.
Call Bryant.
Bryant?
Call Max.
I'll kill you if I have
to. Don't think I won't.
Open up!
I'll plug him right here.
Open the gun safe.
Go on. Open it up!
Lock up the warden.
That wasn't real, was it?
Let's go.
Put your hands up!
Which one of these
here cars is the fastest?
That would be that Ford right
there. It's got the new V-8.
We're gonna take
that one. Go on.
That's Sheriff Lillian
Holley's personal car.
Good.
Mr. Youngblood,
are we clear now?
We are.
Okay, then.
Oh, come on, buddy.
You gotta relax a little
bit. Just take it easy.
Do you know the words
to The Last Round-Up?
Get along,
little dogies
Get along, get along
Get along, little dogies
Get along
Get along, get along
Get along, little dogies
Get along
I'm a-headed for
the last round-up
How did he act?
Was he jolly?
Yes. He sang
part of the way.
Get along, little dogies
Get along, get along
While in Washington today,
President Roosevelt said,
"John Dillinger
is making a mockery
"of the system of justice
in this country."
The passing of John J. McGraw, long-time
manager of the New York Giants...
Hello.
Hey, doll, it's me.
Look, I can't talk long.
You okay?
Yeah.
I heard it on the radio.
How about you?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I'm fine.
Don't come
to Chicago, Johnny.
What's that
supposed to mean?
I promised I'd look
after you, didn't I?
Yes.
Well, then that's
what I'm gonna do.
You know that,
don't you?
Yes.
Look, I think
they're watching me.
I'm gonna come get you out
of there and take care of you.
Baby, don't come
to Chicago!
Say you know it.
Say it.
I know you will
take care of me.
I love you.
Sooner or later,
she will go to him
or he is gonna
come for her.
Say, Sport! Mr. Johnny, you
got to hold it right there.
Can't stay here
no more, Mr. Johnny.
Says who?
Sport's only following
orders. So am I.
They thought
you might come here.
I don't get it.
Talk to your
pal Gilbert.
About what?
You gotta talk
to Gilbert Catena.
Come on. Come on, get out
of here! Beat it! Scram!
The welcome mat
was not out.
I kept hearing your name.
Now, I'm going to ask you once.
And I just did.
Anybody see him come in?
I don't think so.
You want to know
if we're armed?
We're armed.
Calm down.
Calm down. Calm down.
Hey, back to work.
What's the deal, Phil?
Look around.
What do you see?
A whole bunch
of telephones.
You see money.
Last month, there were
independent wire services
letting bookies know who won the
third race at Sportsman's Park,
300 of them nationwide.
Now there's only one, ours.
On October 23rd, you robbed a
bank in Greencastle, Indiana.
You got away
with $74,802.
You thought that
was a big score.
These phones
make that every day.
And it keeps getting made,
day after day after day,
a river of money, and
it gets deeper and wider,
week in and week out, month in
and month out, flowing right to us.
Unless the cops
come through that door.
Which you pay them
not to do.
Right.
Unless you're around.
Then they gotta come through
that door no matter what.
What does that tell you?
I'm popular.
It tells us you're
bad for business.
So the Syndicate's
got a new policy.
All the guys like you,
Karpis, Nelson, Campbell,
we ain't laundering your
money or bonds no more.
You ain't holing up in
our whorehouses anymore.
No armorers, no doctors, no safe
havens, no nothing. You get it?
Personally, you need
something to tide you over?
Good luck to you.
Hamilton has a 34-year-old
sister in Detroit. Arrest her.
Pick up all known Dillinger
associates, doctors, family,
Pierpont's mother
in Indianapolis,
Dillinger's family
in Mooresville.
We suspect them
of harboring.
But Hamilton's family has not
had word from Red in years.
You convince them
to get word.
Create informants,
Agent Purvis.
The suspects are to be
interrogated vigorously, grilled,
no obsolete notions
of sentimentality.
We are in the modern age.
We are making history.
Take direct,
expedient action.
As they say in Italy these days,
"Take off the white gloves!"
Do we understand each
other, Agent Purvis?
These are fine young men
here. What's your name, son?
Harris.
G- men all over the country
have picked up the gauntlet
flung down by the outlaws
and the wanton murderers.
And these junior
crime fighters here,
these Junior G-men, has,
every one of them,
stopped some crime
from occurring
and forestalled an entry into
the black book of criminal deeds.
Today, I am rewarding them
with these medals.
My friend Harris here is
the first. Well done, son.
You can size up a score like
nobody's business, Tommy.
You're a good egg.
But I don't like
Baby Face Nelson.
You got Nelson all wrong, John.
He thinks the world of you.
Hell, the whole country
thinks you're a goddamn hero.
Where's the bank?
Sioux Falls.
Nelson says there's
$800,000 in there.
Says he's got us a sweet
little place to hole up
till after the heat
blows over.
What's he here for?
John, we gotta all be friends, all
right, or this ain't gonna work.
Red told you, after the bank,
we bust out Pierpont and Makley.
It'll take a lot
of careful planning.
Yeah. So?
...and Public Enemy
Number One, John Dillinger.
They may be sitting
amongst you.
They may be in your row.
Turn to your right.
And turn to your left.
If you see them, call the Bureau of
Investigation or your local police.
After the bank,
we'll figure out if we
can bust them out. Okay?
Okay.
"You don't work with
people you don't know
"and you don't work
when you're desperate."
Walter Dietrich.
Remember that?
Walter forgot.
When you're desperate,
that's when you got no choice.
I got one!
What are you doing? Get your
hands up! Get your hands up!
Come on, sugar,
let's go. Come on.
Where's all the damn money
we came here for?
Come on.
Open the door. What
are you looking at, huh?
What are you looking at?
Tommy.
John, let's go!
Let's go!
Get in the goddamn car!
Let's go! Let's go!
How'd you find
this place?
Don't worry. Nobody
will find us. Come on.
How much?
$46, 120.
That'd be less than
$800,000. Am I right?
Am I right?
It's $8,000 a man.
Leave me
my share and get out.
We gotta cut loose
from Nelson.
You gotta
rest up a while.
No.
No. If we don't get out of
here first thing in the morning,
we're gonna wind up dead.
Only you're
gonna make it.
God damn it, don't talk like that, Red.
No, Johnny. I got a
feeling that my time is up.
And when your time is up,
your time's up.
Red,
look here.
Tomorrow morning, Homer,
you and me will go to Reno,
and everything
will be fine.
Give me a shot.
I'll give you the shot if you
tell me where the gang's holed up.
I don't know anything.
Where's Baby Face Nelson?
I don't know!
Where's Dillinger?
I wanna know where
they are. I don't know!
Tell me!
Where are they?
The bullet entered
the back of his head.
It's resting
over his right eye.
Do not interfere.
Do not interfere. His brain is
swelling! He will be dead soon!
He's suffering and I
need to sedate him!
Not yet.
If you interfere,
I will arrest you.
I don't know! Please, give
me a shot! Oh, mother, please!
Tell me where he is!
I don't know!
All right.
Where?
Tell me!
Little Bohemia.
Manitowish, Wisconsin.
Fuck you!
Give me a shot.
Little Bohemia is in
Manitowish, Wisconsin.
Sam, you drive up.
Madala and Clegg, you cut through
the woods. Stay in the trees.
Come up on it
from the south,
close enough to see if
they're in the barroom there.
Rice, Rorer,
come up on it from the
north. The kitchen is there.
You see if they're in what is probably
the dining room. You stay in the trees.
And if he sees them in there? We go in.
And if he doesn't?
We go in anyway.
There's too much
real estate out here.
Too many ways for him
to get out,
too few of us
to block him in.
We need to blockade
the roads behind us.
We need to wait for Cowley's
group to surround him.
Mr. Purvis, this is
not the way to do it.
I will not risk their
escaping the Bureau again.
You and Hurt take the northeast
corner where the road turns.
Cover that and the front.
Campbell, Baum, you're with me.
Thanks,
but we gotta go.
No, come on, stick
around. Let's have a party.
We gotta work tomorrow.
Aw, work's for mugs.
Get out of here!
You wanna see
my James Cagney?
You wanna see my James
Cagney act? Huh? Huh?
What do you see? What do
you say? What do you know?
What's your name, doll?
This your wife, you dumb egg?
Go ahead.
Stop that car!
Bureau of Investigation!
Fire!
Don't shoot!
Get on the floor!
Johnny!
Go!
Someone got out!
Is it Dillinger?
I think so!
Baum, you drive around
the woods. You flank him!
Go.
Go!
Come on, Red, come on. Come
on. We're getting out of here.
Hey, give me the keys
to that car.
Have you...
All you bastards
wear vests,
so I'm gonna give it to you high
and I'm gonna give it to you low.
Carter?
Who was it? Dillinger?
Nelson.
Sir, there's somebody
on the road.
Cowley!
Did you see a car?
A Ford, yeah,
it's going the other way.
Turn it around! Madala,
get in. It's Nelson!
Get in, you dumb bastards!
Get in!
Get in. Come on.
Let's go. Come on.
Where'd
you get the car?
I killed a Fed
by the road.
Faster, Sam!
They're behind us.
Let them have it, Homer!
Steady the car,
God damn it!
Shit!
Homer! Homer!
Come on!
Have you never seen
a man die before?
Hush up.
You gotta let go, John.
Bullshit.
And you gotta
let Billie go, too.
I know you.
You've never let
nobody down.
But this time,
you gotta go on.
You gotta let go.
Right now,
all of Dillinger's
friends are dead.
He is out there.
He is alone.
And there will not be a
better chance to run him down.
Yeah, but he could
be anywhere.
He could be anywhere.
But he is not anywhere, because
what he wants is right here.
I don't believe
in the government,
and I don't believe in the
government spending all its money,
and hence I don't
take any part of it.
And you say no, you...
I ought to refuse to accept the
money. It's government money.
I don't believe in
the government spending.
I'm not gonna take it.
What's she doing?
Still listening
to the radio.
Sir, we have questioned
a source, John Probasco.
We have information that leads
us to believe that they're...
But Dillinger did aid
law enforcement in one way.
He's cited as the reason Congress is
considering the first national crime bill,
making criminal enterprise across
state lines a federal offense.
Meanwhile, in Fargo,
North Dakota...
We're building
coast-to-coast.
We want it nice and quiet,
and they bring this on us?
Frank, calm down. They rob banks. Right.
In one state, then another
state, that's called interstate.
We're coast to coast.
Wake up!
Now they can use
these laws on us.
What time is it?
It's 4:00 a. m., Sunday
morning. What's wrong?
I don't want to sleep.
Why?
Because I want
all the time we got.
What if
we could get out
of here altogether?
Where?
Like Cuba?
Maybe further.
Alvin's got this job. It's
a big job, a lot of dough.
We could go away on it.
We grab a Pan Am
Clipper to Caracas,
scoot on over to Rio
for some fun in the sun,
slide off the map.
We could go dancing
and have
a lot of laughs
any time we want.
Want to take
that ride with me?
Yeah, I want to take
that ride with you.
Where's
the apartment?
Oakley and Potomac.
All right, the bartender's
name is Larry Strong.
He'll give you the keys.
Who brought you?
How did you get here?
A taxi. I took a taxi.
Let's go. Let's go, guys.
Come on! Get her outside.
Where is he?
Where were you meeting?
Where were you hiding out?
Answer him or they'll drop
you in a black hole in Cook County.
Where is he?
I have to go
to the bathroom.
Christ, look what you did.
Where were you
supposed to meet him?
I can't hear you.
I can't hear you!
We were supposed to
meet at our apartment.
Where?
On Addison.
What number?
1148.
When?
Right now.
Miss Roberts, can you
reach Agent Purvis?
No. He's on his way back
from Mooresville, Indiana.
He's going directly
to Cook County Jail.
John Dillinger's holed up
at 1148 Addison.
Where is he?
Well,
way the hell away from
here by now, isn't he?
You wanted to know where
he is, you dumb flatfoot.
Mr. Purvis, those men cannot
treat a woman in this way.
You walked right past him
on State Street.
You were too scared
to look around.
He was at the curb
in that black Buick.
You asked me how I got there,
I told you I took a taxi,
and you believed me?
He dropped me off
and was waiting for me.
And you walked
right past him.
And when my Johnny finds out
how you slapped around his girl,
you know what happens
to you, fat boy?
Uncuff her.
Restroom is
down the hall.
I can't stand up.
Miss Rogers.
Hello.
I'm Marty Zarkovich. I was
told to call you, Mr. Nitti.
I think I can get her
to play ball.
Make sure.
Yes, sir, Mr. Nitti.
What did they say, Anna?
They say they send me
back to Romania.
You know what to do.
Can they fix deportation?
Can they do that?
These guys
can fix anything.
Okay.
I want guarantee.
If you aid us in
apprehending John Dillinger,
I give you my word
I will do everything I can to
influence Bureau of Immigration
to let you stay
in America.
Not enough.
Well, that's all there is.
I want guarantee.
Well, you're not
gonna get one.
I think you did this.
I think you told Immigration to pick
me up and send me back to Romania.
How do you
socialize with him?
We go out.
Maybe tomorrow night.
Maybe not.
Maybe in a week, a month.
Maybe never.
I will not guarantee
what Immigration will do,
but I can guarantee
what I will do.
If you do not cooperate,
you will be on a boat out
of this country in 48 hours.
Do not play games
with me.
Who is "we"?
Me, him, Polly Hamilton,
one of my girls.
How will we know?
I call you on the day
when I know.
Did you get in there?
Did you see her?
Yes, I did.
She palmed me
this note.
She told me
what it said.
That's good advice.
What are you doing here?
Meeting people.
On Tuesday, it'll carry the payrolls
for seven factories around Rockford.
There's two ways in,
two ways out.
Doc cuts the telephone lines
five minutes before.
Train arrives,
you and I go in strong.
Harry handles the door
and the safe.
Jimmy and Freddy drive.
What do you figure?
About $1,500,000
to $1,700,000.
$300,000 each.
Holy cow.
Yeah.
We pull this Tuesday,
I'm gone Wednesday.
Yeah. Where? Cuba?
No.
No. Where I go, I'm gonna have
to go a lot farther than Cuba.
Yeah.
Hi, Jimmy.
What do you say?
Polly, Jimmy's back!
I tell you what, doll.
How about you, Polly and me
go out to a movie tonight?
Get in some refrigeration.
Where do you
want to go?
Maybe the Marbro
or the Biograph.
Jimmy's taking us
to the picture show.
Mmm.
I'll go to the store later and
make fried chicken for dinner.
Where you going?
Streetcar.
I gotta go downtown to get
my waitressing license.
Hang on a minute. I'll take
you. It's too damn hot in here.
Yeah?
Mr. Purvis. Anna Sage.
Afternoon, Miss Sage.
It is tonight!
Anna Sage will be with him
and will wear a white blouse
over an orange skirt.
That is how
we will know it is him.
He may have changed
his appearance.
And we have not learned if he will
go to the Marbro or the Biograph.
Two theaters?
That's right.
What's playing?
Excuse me?
What's playing at the Marbro?
What's playing at the Biograph?
A Shirley Temple movie called
Little Miss Marker is at the Marbro.
The Biograph is playing
a gangster picture
starring Clark Gable,
Manhattan Melodrama.
John Dillinger ain't going
to a Shirley Temple movie.
Sergeants Zarkovich and O'Neill, from
the East Chicago Police Department,
and Agent Winstead will be
at the Biograph, as will I.
Now, Virgil Peterson, you
will coordinate the Marbro.
He will be armed and
extremely dangerous.
Is that it?
Yep.
I'll be right back.
Hold on.
I'll go in with you.
All right.
It might take 10 minutes.
I'll meet you outside.
I'd like to see Babe take
one more swing this season.
But his leg is pretty sore. He takes a
bit of batting practice, but not very much.
What's the score?
Cubs, 3-2,
top of the 7th.
...that's why he's
out of today's game.
The pitch is high.
Ball one.
Broaca, the batter
leading off for the Yankees,
did not see
the ball very well.
What's going on?
Nothing yet.
They haven't shown up
at the Marbro.
Blackie!
Jim!
Well, you old
son of a gun!
I say, you're
looking swell, Jim.
Let's get a load of this
Dempsey-Firpo binge, shall we?
Yeah, yeah. But when will we get
together again? Gee, it's been weeks!
Well, what about
tomorrow night? Saturday?
I will light my cigar
when he's coming out.
Zarkovich, O'Neill,
you and your men
take the hat store right
across from the theater.
Smith, Suran, Clegg, take two
agents, you cover the rear alley.
And Rorer and Rice, you stay in
the car with Reinecke to the north.
Clarence and I are
gonna be in the doorway
30 feet south of
the theater entrance.
Gerry, you're in the tan sedan
just to the north of the entrance.
In case he walks north?
He ain't gonna walk
north, Mr. Purvis.
He's gonna head south, cut through
the alley back to her place.
Madala.
Hello, Gallagher.
Hello, Snow.
Must be something
pretty important,
getting me in here in
the middle of the game.
What do you want?
I want to do a little
favor for a friend.
You're the governor.
You can save his life.
He's guilty.
The jury says so.
Goodbye, Blackie.
Goodbye, Jim.
I can't help it, Blackie.
I'm not gonna
let you die.
I've got to commute you.
You think you're
doing me a favor
by keeping me locked up in this
filthy trap for the rest of my life?
No, thanks. Come on,
warden, let's go.
So long, Blackie.
Kid, keep your chin
up and your nose clean.
Die the way you lived, all of
a sudden, that's the way to go.
Don't drag it out.
Living like that
doesn't mean a thing.
What did he say?
I couldn't hear him.
You take care of this. I
need to go call Washington.
How you doing, Billie?
I'm Special Agent Winstead.
If you've come here to ask
me more damn questions...
"Where's this one
or that one?"
I didn't come here for
you to tell me something.
I came here to
tell you something.
They say you're the man who shot him.
That's right.
One of them.
So why are you
coming here to see me?
To see the damage
you've done?
No.
I came here because
he asked me to.
When he went down,
he said something.
I put my ear
next to his mouth,
and what I think
he said was this.
He said,
"Tell Billie for me,
"'Bye-bye, blackbird."'